<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">IJCNLP-2017 Task 2: Dimensional Sentiment Analysis for Chinese Phrases</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Liang-Chih</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
							<email>lcyu@saturn.yzu.edu.tw</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Information Management</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Yuan Ze University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="TW">Taiwan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Innovative Center for Big Data and Digital Convergence</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Yuan Ze University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="TW">Taiwan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Lung-Hao</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
							<email>lhlee@ntnu.edu.tw</email>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Graduate Institute of Library and Information Studies</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">National Taiwan Normal University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Jin</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
							<email>wangjin@ynu.edu.cn</email>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">School of Information Science and Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Yunnan University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Yunnan</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Kam-Fai</forename><surname>Wong</surname></persName>
							<email>kfwong@se.cuhk.edu.hk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="institution">The Chinese University of Hong Kong</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Hong Kong</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">IJCNLP-2017 Task 2: Dimensional Sentiment Analysis for Chinese Phrases</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-08-25T17:31+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>This paper presents the IJCNLP 2017 shared task on Dimensional Sentiment Analysis for Chinese Phrases (DSAP) which seeks to identify a real-value sentiment score of Chinese single words and multi-word phrases in the both valence and arousal dimensions. Valence represents the degree of pleasant and unpleasant (or positive and negative) feelings, and arousal represents the degree of excitement and calm. Of the 19 teams registered for this shared task for twodimensional sentiment analysis, 13 submitted results. We expected that this evaluation campaign could produce more advanced dimensional sentiment analysis techniques, especially for Chinese affective computing. All data sets with gold standards and scoring script are made publicly available to researchers.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Sentiment analysis has emerged as a leading technique to automatically identify affective information within texts. In sentiment analysis, affective states are generally represented using either categorical or dimensional approaches <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Calvo and Kim, 2013)</ref>. The categorical approach represents affective states as several discrete classes (e.g., positive, negative, neutral), while the dimensional approach represents affective states as continuous numerical values on multiple dimensions, such as valence-arousal (VA) space <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Russell, 1980)</ref>, as shown in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">1</ref>. The valence represents the degree of pleasant and unpleasant (or positive and negative) feelings, and the arousal represents the degree of excitement and calm. Based on this twodimensional representation, any affective state can be represented as a point in the VA coordinate plane by determining the degrees of valence and arousal of given words <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Wei et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Malandrakis et al., 2011;</ref> or texts <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Kim et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Paltoglou et al, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Wang et al., 2016b)</ref>. Dimensional sentiment analysis has emerged as a compelling topic for research with applications including antisocial behavior detection <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Munezero et al., 2011)</ref>, mood analysis <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(De Choudhury et al., 2012)</ref> and product review ranking <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Ren and Nickerson, 2014)</ref> The IJCNLP 2017 features a shared task for dimensional sentiment analysis for Chinese words, providing an evaluation platform for the development and implementation of advanced techniques for affective computing. Sentiment lexicons with valence-arousal ratings are useful resources for the development of dimensional sentiment applications. Due to the limited availability of such VA lexicons, especially for Chinese, the objective of the task is to automatically acquire the valence-arousal ratings of Chinese affective words and phrases.</p><p>The rest of this paper is organized as follows. Section II describes the task in detail. Section III introduces the constructed datasets. Section IV proposes evaluation metrics. Section V reports the results of the participants' approaches. Conclusions are finally drawn in Section VI.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Task Description</head><p>This task seeks to evaluate the capability of systems for predicting dimensional sentiments of Chinese words and phrases. For a given word or phrase, participants were asked to provide a realvalued score from 1 to 9 for both the valence and arousal dimensions, respectively indicating the degree from most negative to most positive for valence, and from most calm to most excited for arousal. The input format is "term_id, term", and the output format is "term_id, valence_rating, arousal_rating". Below are the input/output formats of the example words "好" (good), "非常好" (very good), "滿意" (satisfy) and "不滿意" (not satisfy). with valence-arousal ratings. For multi-word phrases, we first selected a set of modifiers such as negators (e.g., not), degree adverbs (e.g., very) and modals (e.g., would). These modifiers were combined with the affective words in CVAW to form multi-word phrases. The frequency of each phrase was then retrieved from a large web-based corpus. Only phrases with a frequency greater than or equal to 3 were retained as candidates. To avoid several modifiers dominating the whole dataset, each modifier (or modifier combination) can have at most 50 phrases. In addition, the phrases were selected to maximize the balance between positive and negative words. Finally, a total of 3,000 phrases were collected by excluding unusual and semantically incomplete candidate phrases, of which 2,250 phrases were randomly selected as the training set according to the proportions of each modifier (or modifier combination) in the original set, and the remaining 750 phrases were used as the test set.</p><p>Test set: For single words, we selected 750 words that were not included in the CVAW 2.0 from NTUSD (Ku and Chen, 2007) using the same method presented in our previous task on Dimensional Sentiment Analysis for Chinese Words . Each single word in both training and test sets was annotated with valence-arousal ratings by five annotators and the average ratings were taken as ground truth. Each multi-word phrase was rated by at least 10 different annotators. Once the rating process was finished, a corpus clean up procedure was performed to remove outlier ratings that did not fall within the mean plus/minus 1.5 standard deviations. They were then excluded from the calculation of the average ratings for each phrase.</p><p>The policy of this shared task was implemented as is an open test. That is, in addition to the above official datasets, participating teams were allowed to use other publicly available data for system development, but such sources should be specified in the final technical report.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Evaluation Metrics</head><p>Prediction performance is evaluated by examining the difference between machine-predicted ratings and human-annotated ratings, in which valence and arousal are treated independently. The evaluation metrics include Mean Absolute Error (MAE) </p><formula xml:id="formula_0">| = = − ∑ n i i i MAE A P n (1)  Pearson correlation coefficient (PCC) 1 1 ( )( ) 1 σ σ = − − = − ∑ n i i i A P A A P P PCC n (2)</formula><p>where Ai is the actual value, Pi is the predicted value, n is the number of test samples, A and P respectively denote the arithmetic mean of A and P, and σ is the standard deviation. The MAE measures the error rate and the PCC measures the linear correlation between the actual values and the predicted values. A lower MAE and a higher PCC indicate more accurate prediction performance.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Evaluation Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Participants</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Baseline</head><p>We implemented a baseline by training a linear regression model using word vectors as the only features. For single words, the regression was implemented by directly training word vectors to determine VA scores. Given a word wi, the baseline regression model is defined as ( ) ( ) </p><formula xml:id="formula_1">= ⋅ + = ⋅ + (3)</formula><p>where Valwi and Arowi respectively denote the valence and arousal ratings of wi. W and b respec-tively denote the weights and bias. For phrases, we first calculate the mean vector of the constituent words in the phrase, considering each modifier word can also obtain its word vector. Give a phrase pj, its representation can be obtained by, where wi∈pj is the word in phrase pj. The regression was then trained using vec(pj) as a feature, defined as ( ) ( )  The word vectors were trained on the Chinese Wiki Corpus 2 using the CBOW model of word2vec 3 <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Mikolov et al., 2013a;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">2013b</ref>) (di-mensionality=300 and window size=5).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3">Results</head><p>Tables 2 shows the results of valence-arousal prediction for single words. The three best performing systems are summarized as follows. Tables <ref type="table" target="#tab_7">3</ref> shows the results of valence-arousal prediction for multi-word phrases. The three best performing systems are summarized as follows.   Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_9">4</ref> shows the overall results for both single words and multi-word phrases. We rank the MAE and PCC independently and calculate the mean rank (average of MAE rank and PCC rank) for ordering system performance. The three best performing systems are THU_NGN, AL_I_NLP and CKIP.</p><p>Table <ref type="table">5</ref> summarizes the approaches for each participating system. CASIA, SAM and XMUT did not submit reports on their developed methods. Nearly all teams used word embeddings. The most commonly used word embeddings were word2vec <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Mikolov et al., 2013a;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">2013b)</ref> and GloVe <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Pennington et al., 2014)</ref>. Others included FastText 4 <ref type="bibr">(Bojanowski et al., 2017)</ref>, characterenhanced word embedding <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Chen et al., 2015)</ref> and Cw2vec <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Cao et al., 2017</ref>  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusions</head><p>This study describes an overview of the IJCNLP 2017 shared task on dimensional sentiment analysis for Chinese phrases, including task design, data preparation, performance metrics, and evaluation results. Regardless of actual performance, all submissions contribute to the common effort to develop dimensional approaches for affective computing, and the individual report in the proceedings provide useful insights into Chinese sentiment analysis. We hope the data sets collected and annotated for this shared task can facilitate and expedite future development in this research area. Therefore, all data sets with gold standard and scoring script are publicly available 5 .</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Two-dimensional valence-arousal space.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Arousal MAE: CKIP, THU_NGN and NTOU.Arousal PCC: THU_NGN, CKIP and NTOU.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>In the testing phase, each team was allowed to submit at most two runs. Three teams submitted only one run, while the other 10 teams submitted two runs for a total of 23 runs.</figDesc><table><row><cell>summarizes the submission statistics for</cell></row><row><cell>19 participating teams including 7 from universi-</cell></row><row><cell>ties and research institutes in China (CASIA, G-</cell></row><row><cell>719, LDCCNLP, SAM, THU_NGN, TeeMo and</cell></row><row><cell>XMUT), 6 from Taiwan (CIAL, CKIP, NCTU-</cell></row><row><cell>NTUT, NCYU, NLPSA and NTOU), 2 private</cell></row><row><cell>films (AL_I_NLP and Mainiway AI), 2 teams</cell></row><row><cell>from India (DeepCybErNet and Dlg), one from</cell></row><row><cell>Europe (DCU) and one team from USA (UIUC).</cell></row><row><cell>Thirteen of the 19 registered teams submitted their</cell></row><row><cell>testing results.</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Submission statistics for all participating teams.</figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Comparative results of valence-arousal prediction for single words.</figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Comparative results of valence-arousal prediction for multi-word phrases.</figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_9"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Comparative results of valence-arousal prediction for both words and phrases. E-HowNet<ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Huang et al., 2008)</ref> predictor (CKIP) and heuristic-based ADV Weight List (CIAL).</figDesc><table /></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>References</head><p>Piotr Bojanowski, Edouard Grave, Armand Joulin, and Tomas <ref type="bibr">Mikolov. 2017</ref>. Enriching word vectors with subword information. Transactions of the Association for Computational Linguistics 5:135-146.  </p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Emotions in text: dimensional and categorical models</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rafael</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sunghwan Mac</forename><surname>Calvo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Intelligence</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="527" to="543" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Investigating chinese word embeddings based on stroke information</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Shaosheng</forename><surname>Cao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Wei</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jun</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Xiaolong</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Joint learning of characterand word embeddings</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Xinxiong</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lei</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Zhiyuan</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Maosong</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Huan-Bo</forename><surname>Luan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the 25th International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI-15)</title>
				<meeting>of the 25th International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI-15)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1236" to="1242" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Not all moods are created equal! Exploring human emotional states in social media</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Scott</forename><surname>Munmun De Choudhury</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Counts</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Gamon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the 6th International AAAI Conference on Weblogs and Social Media (ICWSM-12)</title>
				<meeting>of the 6th International AAAI Conference on Weblogs and Social Media (ICWSM-12)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="66" to="73" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Knowledge representation for comparative constructions in extended-HowNet. Language and Linguistics</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Shu-Ling</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yueh-Yin</forename><surname>Shih</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Keh-Jiann</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="395" to="413" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evaluation of unsupervised emotion models to textual affect recognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alessandro</forename><surname>Sunghwan Mac Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rafael</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Valitutti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Calvo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the NAACL HLT 2010 Workshop on Computational Approaches to Analysis and Generation of Emotion in Text</title>
				<meeting>of the NAACL HLT 2010 Workshop on Computational Approaches to Analysis and Generation of Emotion in Text</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="62" to="70" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mining Opinions from the Web: Beyond Relevance Retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Wei</forename><surname>Lun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Hsin-Hsi</forename><surname>Ku</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of American Society for Information Science and Technology, Special Issue on Mining Web Resources for Enhancing Information Retrieval</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">58</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1838" to="1850" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Kernel models for affective lexicon creation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nikos</forename><surname>Malandrakis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alexandros</forename><surname>Potamianos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Elias</forename><surname>Iosif</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Shrikanth</forename><surname>Narayanan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of IN-TERSPEECH-11</title>
				<meeting>of IN-TERSPEECH-11</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2977" to="2980" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Distributed representations of words and phrases and their compositionality</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tomas</forename><surname>Mikolov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kai</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Greg</forename><surname>Corrado</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><surname>Dean</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Annual Conference on Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems (NIPS-13)</title>
				<meeting>the Annual Conference on Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems (NIPS-13)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="9" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efficient estimation of word representations in vector space</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tomas</forename><surname>Mikolov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Greg</forename><surname>Corrado</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kai</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><surname>Dean</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR-2013)</title>
				<meeting>the International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR-2013)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="12" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Towards automatic detection of antisocial behavior from texts</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Myriam</forename><surname>Munezero</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tuomo</forename><surname>Kakkonen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Calkin</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Montero</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the Workshop on Sentiment Analysis where AI meets Psychology (SAAIP) at IJCNLP-11</title>
				<meeting>of the Workshop on Sentiment Analysis where AI meets Psychology (SAAIP) at IJCNLP-11</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="20" to="27" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Predicting emotional responses to long informal text</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Georgios</forename><surname>Paltoglou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mathias</forename><surname>Theunis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Trans. Affective Computing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="106" to="115" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Arvid Kappas, and Mike Thelwall</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">GloVe: Global vectors for word representation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><surname>Pennington</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Socher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
				<meeting>the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1532" to="1543" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Online review systems: How emotional language drives sales</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jie</forename><surname>Ren</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Nickerson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the 20th Americas Conference on Information Systems (AMCIS-14)</title>
				<meeting>of the 20th Americas Conference on Information Systems (AMCIS-14)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A circumplex model of affect</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">James</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Russell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1161</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1980" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A regression approach to affective rating of Chinese words from ANEW</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Wen-Li</forename><surname>Wei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Chung-Hsien</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jen-Chun</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the 4th International Conference on Affective Computing and Intelligent Interaction (ACII-11)</title>
				<meeting>of the 4th International Conference on Affective Computing and Intelligent Interaction (ACII-11)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="121" to="131" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Building Chinese affective resources in valence-arousal dimensions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Liang-Chih</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lung-Hao</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Shuai</forename><surname>Hao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jin</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yunchao</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of NAACL/HLT-16</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">Robert</forename><surname>Hu</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">Xuejie</forename><surname>Lai</surname></persName>
			<persName><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting>of NAACL/HLT-16</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016-06" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="540" to="545" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Overview of the IALP 2016 shared task on dimensional sentiment analysis for Chinese words</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Liang-Chih</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lung-Hao</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kam-Fai</forename><surname>Wong</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the 20th International Conference on Asian Language Processing (IALP-16)</title>
				<meeting>of the 20th International Conference on Asian Language essing (IALP-16)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="156" to="160" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Community-based weighted graph model for valence-arousal prediction of affective words</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jin</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Liang-Chih</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Lai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Xuejie</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE/ACM Trans. Audio, Speech and Language Processing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1957" to="1968" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dimensional sentiment analysis using a regional CNN-LSTM model</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jin</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Liang-Chih</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">Robert</forename><surname>Lai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Xuejie</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL-16)</title>
				<meeting>of the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL-16)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="225" to="230" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
