<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Semeval-2013 Task 8: Cross-lingual Textual Entailment for Content Synchronization</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Matteo</forename><surname>Negri</surname></persName>
							<email>negri@fbk.eu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">FBK-irst Trento</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="IT">Italy</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Alessandro</forename><surname>Marchetti</surname></persName>
							<email>amarchetti@celct.it</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<address>
									<settlement>Trento</settlement>
									<country key="IT">Italy</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Yashar</forename><surname>Mehdad</surname></persName>
							<email>mehdad@cs.ubc.ca</email>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<address>
									<settlement>Vancouver</settlement>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Luisa</forename><surname>Bentivogli</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">FBK-irst Trento</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="IT">Italy</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Danilo</forename><surname>Giampiccolo</surname></persName>
							<email>giampiccolo@celct.it</email>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<address>
									<settlement>Trento</settlement>
									<country key="IT">Italy</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Semeval-2013 Task 8: Cross-lingual Textual Entailment for Content Synchronization</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-08-25T17:26+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>This paper presents the second round of the task on Cross-lingual Textual Entailment for Content Synchronization, organized within SemEval-2013. The task was designed to promote research on semantic inference over texts written in different languages, targeting at the same time a real application scenario. Participants were presented with datasets for different language pairs, where multi-directional entailment relations ("forward", "backward", "bidirectional", "no entailment") had to be identified. We report on the training and test data used for evaluation, the process of their creation, the participating systems (six teams, 61 runs), the approaches adopted and the results achieved.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>The cross-lingual textual entailment task  addresses textual entailment (TE) recognition <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Dagan and Glickman, 2004)</ref> under the new dimension of cross-linguality, and within the new challenging application scenario of content synchronization. Given two texts in different languages, the cross-lingual textual entailment (CLTE) task consists of deciding if the meaning of one text can be inferred from the meaning of the other text. Crosslinguality represents an interesting direction for research on recognizing textual entailment (RTE), especially due to its possible application in a variety of tasks. Among others (e.g. question answering, information retrieval, information extraction, and document summarization), multilingual content synchronization represents a challenging application scenario to evaluate CLTE recognition components geared to the identification of sentence-level semantic relations.</p><p>Given two documents about the same topic written in different languages (e.g. Wikipedia pages), the content synchronization task consists of automatically detecting and resolving differences in the information they provide, in order to produce aligned, mutually enriched versions of the two documents <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Monz et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Bronner et al., 2012)</ref>. Towards this objective, a crucial requirement is to identify the information in one page that is either equivalent or novel (more informative) with respect to the content of the other. The task can be naturally cast as an entailment recognition problem, where bidirectional and unidirectional entailment judgements for two text fragments are respectively mapped into judgements about semantic equivalence and novelty. The task can also be seen as a machine translation evaluation problem, where judgements about semantic equivalence and novelty depend on the possibility to fully or partially translate a text fragment into the other.</p><p>The recent advances on monolingual TE on the one hand, and the methodologies used in Statistical Machine Translation (SMT) on the other, offer promising solutions to approach the CLTE task. In line with a number of systems that model the RTE task as a similarity problem (i.e. handling similarity scores between T and H as features contributing to the entailment decision), the standard sentence and word alignment programs used in SMT offer a strong baseline for CLTE <ref type="bibr"></ref> Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref>: Example of SP-EN CLTE pairs. . However, although representing a solid starting point to approach the problem, similarity-based techniques are just approximations, open to significant improvements coming from semantic inference at the multilingual level (e.g. cross-lingual entailment rules such as "perro"→"animal"). Taken in isolation, similaritybased techniques clearly fall short of providing an effective solution to the problem of assigning directions to the entailment relations (especially in the complex CLTE scenario, where entailment relations are multi-directional). Thanks to the contiguity between CLTE, TE and SMT, the proposed task provides an interesting scenario to approach the issues outlined above from different perspectives, and offers large room for mutual improvement.</p><p>Building on the success of the first CLTE evaluation organized within SemEval-2012 <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Negri et al., 2012a)</ref>, the remainder of this paper describes the second evaluation round organized within SemEval-2013. The following sections provide an overview of the datasets used, the participating systems, the approaches adopted, the achieved results, and the lessons learned.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">The task</head><p>Given a pair of topically related text fragments (T1 and T2) in different languages, the CLTE task consists of automatically annotating it with one of the following entailment judgements (see Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref> for Spanish/English examples of each judgement):</p><p>• bidirectional (T1→T2 &amp; T1←T2): the two fragments entail each other (semantic equivalence);</p><p>• forward (T1→T2 &amp; T1 ←T2): unidirectional entailment from T1 to T2;</p><p>• backward (T1 →T2 &amp; T1←T2): unidirectional entailment from T2 to T1;</p><p>• no entailment (T1 →T2 &amp; T1 ←T2): there is no entailment between T1 and T2 in either direction;</p><p>In this task, both T1 and T2 are assumed to be true statements. Although contradiction is relevant from an application-oriented perspective, contradictory pairs are not present in the dataset.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Dataset description</head><p>The CLTE-2013 dataset is composed of four CLTE corpora created for the following language combinations: Spanish/English (SP-EN), Italian/English (IT-EN), French/English (FR-EN), German/English <ref type="bibr">(DE-EN)</ref>. Each corpus consists of 1,500 sentence pairs (1,000 for training and 500 for test), balanced across the four entailment judgements.</p><p>In this year's evaluation, as training set we used the CLTE-2012 corpus 1 that was created for the SemEval-2012 evaluation exercise 2 (including both training and test sets). The CLTE-2013 test set was created from scratch, following the methodology described in the next section.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Data collection and annotation</head><p>To collect the entailment pairs for the 2013 test set we adopted a slightly modified version of the crowdsourcing methodology followed to create the CLTE-2012 corpus . The main difference with last year's procedure is that we did not take advantage of crowdsourcing for the whole data collection process, but only for part of it.</p><p>As for CLTE-2012, the collection and annotation process consists of the following steps:</p><p>1. First, English sentences were manually extracted from Wikipedia and Wikinews. The selected sentences represent one of the elements (T1) of each entailment pair;</p><p>2. Next, each T1 was modified in various ways in order to obtain a corresponding T2. While in the CLTE-2012 dataset the whole T2 creation process was carried out through crowdsourcing, for the CLTE-2013 test set we crowdsourced only the first phase of T1 modification, namely the creation of paraphrases. Focusing on the creation of high quality paraphrases, we followed the crowdsourcing methodology experimented in <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Negri et al. (2012b)</ref>, in which a paraphrase is obtained through an iterative modification process of an original sentence, by asking workers to introduce meaningpreserving lexical and syntactic changes. At each round of the iteration, new workers are presented with the output of the previous iteration in order to increase divergence from the original sentence. At the end of the process, only the more divergent paraphrases according to the Lesk score <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Lesk, 1986)</ref> are selected. As for the second phase of T2 creation process, this year it was carried out by expert annotators, who followed the same criteria used last year for the crowdsourced tasks, i.e. i) remove information from the input (paraphrased) sentence and ii) add information from sentences surrounding T1 in the source article;</p><p>3. Each T2 was then paired to the original T1, and the resulting pairs were annotated with one of the four entailment judgements. In order to reduce the correlation between the difference in sentences' length and entailment judgements, only the pairs where the difference between the number of words in T1 and T2 (length diff ) was below a fixed threshold (10 words) were retained. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> The final result is a monolingual English dataset annotated with multi-directional entailment judgements, which are well distributed over length diff values ranging from 0 to 9; 4. In order to create the cross-lingual datasets, each English T1 was manually translated into 3 Such constraint has been applied in order to focus as much as possible on semantic aspects of the problem, by reducing the applicability of simple association rules such as IF length(T1)&gt;length(T2) THEN T1→T2.</p><p>four different languages (i.e. Spanish, German, Italian and French) by expert translators; 5. By pairing the translated T1 with the corresponding T2 in English, four cross-lingual datasets were obtained.</p><p>To ensure the good quality of the datasets, all the collected pairs were cross-annotated and filtered to retain only those pairs with full agreement in the entailment judgement between two expert annotators. The final result is a multilingual parallel entailment corpus, where T1s are in 5 different languages (i.e. English, Spanish, German, Italian, and French), and T2s are in English. It is worth mentioning that the monolingual English corpus, a byproduct of our data collection methodology, will be publicly released as a further contribution to the research community.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Dataset statistics</head><p>As described in section 3.1, the methodology followed to create the training and test sets was the same except for the crowdsourced tasks. This allowed us to obtain two datasets with the same balance across the entailment judgements, and to keep under control the distribution of the pairs for different length diff values in each language combination.</p><p>Training Set. The training set is composed of 1,000 CLTE pairs for each language combination, balanced across the four entailment judgements (bidirectional, forward, backward, and no entailment). As shown in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">1</ref>, our data collection procedure led to a dataset where the majority of the pairs falls in the +5 -5 length diff range for each language pair (67.2% on average across the four language pairs). This characteristic is particularly relevant as our assumption is that such data distribution makes entailment judgements based on mere surface features such as sentence length ineffective, thus encouraging the development of alternative, deeper processing strategies.</p><p>Test Set. The test set is composed of 500 entailment pairs for each language combination, balanced across the four entailment judgements. As shown in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">2</ref>, also in this dataset the majority of the collected entailment pairs is uniformly distributed    and test sets, the ideal objective of a full homogeneity between the datasets for these two languages was difficult to reach.</p><p>Complete details about the distribution of the pairs in terms of length diff for the four crosslingual corpora in the test set are provided in Figure <ref type="figure">2</ref>. Vertical bars represent, for each length diff value, the proportion of pairs belonging to the four entailment classes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Evaluation metrics and baselines</head><p>Evaluation results have been automatically computed by comparing the entailment judgements returned by each system with those manually assigned by human annotators in the gold standard. The metrics used for systems' ranking is accuracy over the whole test set, i.e. the number of correct judgements out of the total number of judgements in the test set. Additionally, we calculated precision, recall, and F1 measures for each of the four entailment judgement categories taken separately. These scores aim at giving participants the possibility to gain clearer insights into their system's behaviour on the entailment phenomena relevant to the task.</p><p>To allow comparison with the CLTE-2012 results, the same three baselines were calculated on the CLTE-2013 test set for each language combination. The first one is the 0.25 accuracy score obtained by assigning each test pair in the balanced dataset to one of the four classes. The other two baselines consider the length difference between T1 and T2:</p><p>• Composition of binary judgements (Binary). To calculate this baseline an SVM classifier is trained to take binary entailment decisions ("YES", "NO"). The classifier uses length(T1)/length(T2) and length(T2)/length(T1) as features respectively to check for entailment from T1 to T2 and viceversa. For each test pair, the unidirectional judgements returned by the two classifiers are composed into a single multi-directional judgement ("YES-YES"="bidirectional", "YES-NO"="forward", "NO-YES"="backward", "NO-NO"="no entailment");</p><p>• Multi-class classification (Multi-class). A single SVM classifier is trained with the same features to directly assign to each pair one of the four entailment judgements.</p><p>Both the baselines have been calculated with the LIBSVM package (Chang and Lin, 2011), using default parameters. Baseline results are reported in Table 3.</p><p>Although the four CLTE datasets are derived from the same monolingual EN-EN corpus, baseline results present slight differences due to the effect of translation into different languages. With respect to last year's evaluation, we can observe a slight drop in the binary classification baseline results. This might be due to the fact that the length distribution of examples is slightly different this year. However, there are no significant differences between the multi-class baseline results of this year in comparison with the previous round results. This might suggest that multi-class classification is a more robust approach for recognizing multi-directional entailment relations. Moreover, both baselines failed in capturing the "no-entailment" examples in all datasets (F 1 no−entailment = 0).  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>SP-EN IT-EN FR-EN DE-EN</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Submitted runs and results</head><p>Like in the 2012 round of the CLTE task, participants were allowed to submit up to five runs for each language combination. A total of twelve teams registered for participation and downloaded the training set. Out of them, six 4 submitted valid runs. Five teams produced submissions for all the four language combinations, while one team participated only in the DE-EN task. In total, 61 runs have been submitted and evaluated (16 for DE-EN, and 15 for each of the other language pairs). Accuracy results are reported in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">4</ref>. As can be seen from the table, the performance of the best systems is quite similar across the four language combinations, with the best submissions achieving results in the 43.4-45.8% accuracy interval. Similarly, also average and median results are close to each other, with a small drop on DE-EN. This drop might be explained by the difference between the training and test set with respect to the length diff feature. Moreover, the performance of DE-EN automatic translation might affect approaches based on "pivoting", (i.e. addressing CLTE by automatically translating T1 in the same language of T2, as described in Section 6).  Compared to the results achieved last year, shown in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_8">5</ref>, a sensible decrease in the highest scores can be observed. While in CLTE-2012 the top systems achieved an accuracy well above 0.5 (with a maximum of 0.632 in SP-EN), the results for this year are far below such level (the peak is now at 45,8% for FR-EN). A slight decrease with respect to 2012 can also be noted for average performances. However, it's worth remarking the general increase of the lowest and median scores, which are less sensitive to isolate outstanding results achieved by single teams. This indicates that a progress in CLTE research has been made building on the lessons learned after the first round of the initiative.</p><p>To better understand the behaviour of each system, Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_10">6</ref> provides separate precision, recall, and F1 scores for each entailment judgement, calculated over the best runs of each participating team. In contrast to CLTE-2012, where the "bidirectional" and "no entailment" categories consistently proved to be more problematic than "forward" and "backward" judgements, this year's results are more homogeneous across the different classes. Nevertheless, on average, the classification of "bidirectional" pairs is still worse for three language pairs (SP-EN, <ref type="bibr">IT-EN and FR-EN)</ref>, and results for "no entailment" are lower for two of them <ref type="bibr">(SP-EN and DE-EN)</ref>.  As regards the comparison with the baselines, this year's results confirm that the length diff -based baselines are hard to beat. More specifically, most of the systems are slightly above the binary classification baseline (with the exception of the DE-EN dataset where only two systems out of six outperformed it), whereas for all the language combinations the multi-class baseline was beaten only by the best participating system.</p><p>This shows that, despite the effort in keeping the distribution of the entailment classes uniform across different length diff values, eliminating the correlation between sentence length and correct entailment decisions is difficult. As a consequence, although disregarding semantic aspects of the problem, features considering length information are quite effective in terms of overall accuracy. Such features, however, perform rather poorly when dealing with challenging cases (e.g. "no-entailment"), which are better handled by participating systems.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Approaches</head><p>A rough classification of the approaches adopted by participants can be made along two orthogonal dimensions, namely:</p><p>• Pivoting vs. Cross-lingual. Pivoting methods rely on the automatic translation of one of the two texts (either single words or the entire sentence) into the language of the other (typically English) in order perform monolingual TE recognition. Cross-lingual methods assign entailment judgements without preliminary translation.</p><p>• Composition of binary judgements vs. Multi-class classification. Compositional approaches map unidirectional ("YES"/"NO")  entailment decisions taken separately into single judgements (similar to the Binary baseline in Section 4). Methods based on multi-class classification directly assign one of the four entailment judgements to each test pair (similar to our Multi-class baseline).</p><p>In contrast with CLTE-2012, where the combination of pivoting and compositional methods was the option adopted by the majority of the approaches, this year's solutions do not show a clear trend. Concerning the former dimension, participating systems are equally distributed in cross-lingual and pivoting methods relying on external automatic translation tools. Regarding the latter dimension, in addition to compositional and multi-class strategies, also alternative solutions that leverage more sophisticated meta-classification strategies have been proposed.</p><p>Besides the recourse to MT tools (e.g. Google Translate), other tools and resources used by participants include: WordNet, word alignment tools (e.g. Giza++), part-of-speech taggers (e.g. Stanford POS Tagger), stemmers (e.g. Snowball), machine learning libraries (e.g. Weka, SVMlight), parallel corpora (e.g. Europarl), and stopword lists. More in detail: <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Turchi and Negri, 2013</ref>) adopts a supervised learning method based on features that consider word alignments between the two sentences obtained with GIZA++ <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Och et al., 2003</ref>  <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Kouylekov and Negri, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Negri et al., 2009)</ref> are used to extract features to train a meta-classifier. Such classifier combines binary decisions ("YES"/"NO") taken separately for each of the four CLTE judgements.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">ALTN [cross-lingual, compositional]</formula><p>ECNUCS [pivoting, multi-class] (Jiang and Man, 2013) uses Google Translate to obtain the English translation of each T1. After a pre-processing step aimed at maximizing the commonalities between the two sentences (e.g. abbreviation replacement), a number of features is extracted to train a multi-class SVM classifier. Such features consider information about sentence length, text similarity/difference measures, and syntactic information.</p><p>SoftCard [pivoting, multi-class] <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Jimenez et al., 2013)</ref> after automatic translation with Google Translate, uses SVMs to learn entailment decisions based on information about the cardinality of: T1, T2, their intersection and their union. Cardinalities are computed in different ways, considering tokens in T1 and T2, their IDF, and their similarity.</p><p>Umelb [cross-lingual, pivoting, compositional] ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Graham et al., 2013)</ref> adopts both pivoting and cross-lingual approaches. For the latter, GIZA++ was used to compute word alignments between the input sentences. Word alignment features are used to train binary SVM classifiers whose decisions are eventually composed into CLTE judgements.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Conclusion</head><p>Following the success of the first round of the Crosslingual Textual Entailment for Content Synchroniza-5 http://translate.google.com/ tion task organized within SemEval-2012, a second evaluation task has been organized within SemEval-2013. Despite the decrease in the number of participants (six teams -four less than in the first round -submitted a total of 61 runs) the new experience is still positive. In terms of data, a new test set has been released, extending the old one with 500 new CLTE pairs. The resulting 1,500 cross-lingual pairs, aligned over four language combinations (in addition to the monolingual English version), and annotated with multiple entailment relations, represent a significant contribution to the research community and a solid starting point for further developments. <ref type="bibr">6</ref> In terms of results, in spite of a significant decrease of the top scores, the increase of both median and lower results demonstrates some encouraging progress in CLTE research. Such progress is also demonstrated by the variety of the approaches proposed. While in the first round most of the teams adopted more intuitive and "simpler" solutions based on pivoting (i.e. translation of T1 and T2 in the same language) and compositional entailment decision strategies, this year new ideas and more complex solutions have emerged. Pivoting and cross-lingual approaches are equally distributed, and new classification methods have been proposed. Our hope is that the large room for improvement, the increase of available data, and the potential of CLTE as a way to address complex NLP tasks and applications will motivate further research on the proposed problem.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 2: Pair distribution in the 2013 test set: total number of pairs (y-axis) for different length diff values (x-axis).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Training set pair distribution within the -5/+5 length diff range.in the [-5,+5] length diff range (68.1% on average across the four language pairs).However, comparing training and test set for each language pair, it can be seen that while the Spanish-English and Italian-English datasets are homogeneous with respect to the length diff feature, the French-English and German-English datasets present noticeable differences between training and test set. These figures show that, despite the considerable effort spent to produce comparable training</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>SP-EN</cell><cell>IT-EN</cell><cell>FR-EN</cell><cell>DE-EN</cell></row><row><cell>backward</cell><cell>82</cell><cell>89</cell><cell>82</cell><cell>102</cell></row><row><cell>bidirectional</cell><cell>89</cell><cell>92</cell><cell>90</cell><cell>106</cell></row><row><cell>forward</cell><cell>69</cell><cell>78</cell><cell>76</cell><cell>98</cell></row><row><cell>no entailment</cell><cell>71</cell><cell>80</cell><cell>59</cell><cell>100</cell></row><row><cell>ALL</cell><cell>311</cell><cell>339</cell><cell>307</cell><cell>406</cell></row><row><cell>% (out of 500)</cell><cell>62.2</cell><cell>67.8</cell><cell>61.4</cell><cell>81.2</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Test set pair distribution within the -5/+5 length diff range.</figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table /><note>Baseline accuracy results.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6"><head>Table 4</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>: CLTE-2013 accuracy results (61 runs) over the</cell></row><row><cell>4 language combinations. Highest, average, median and</cell></row><row><cell>lowest scores are calculated considering only the best run</cell></row><row><cell>for each team (*task organizers' system).</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_8"><head>Table 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>CLTE-2012 accuracy results. Highest, average, median and lowest scores are calculated considering only the best run for each team.</figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_10"><head>Table 6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Precision, recall and F1 scores, calculated for each team's best run for all the language combinations.</figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_11"><head></head><label></label><figDesc><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Vilariño et al., 2013)</ref> adopts a pivoting method based on translating T1 into the language of T2 and vice versa (using Google Translate 5 ). Similarity measures (e.g. Jaccard index) and features based on n-gram overlap, computed at the level of words and part of speech categories, are used (either alone or in combination) by different classification strategies including: multi-class, a meta-classifier</figDesc><table><row><cell>). Binary entailment judgements are taken separately, and combined into final CLTE decisions. BUAP [pivoting, multi-class and meta-classifier] ((i.e. combining the output of 2/3/4-class classifiers), and majority voting. CELI [cross-lingual, meta-classifier] (Kouylekov, 2013) uses dictionaries for word matching, and a multilingual corpus extracted from Wikipedia for term weighting. A variety of distance measures implemented in the RTE system EDITS</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">http://www.celct.it/resources.php?id page=CLTE 2 http://www.cs.york.ac.uk/semeval-2012/task8/</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4">Including the task organizers.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="6">Together with the datasets derived from translation of the RTE data, this is the only material currently available to train and evaluate CLTE systems.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>This work has been partially supported by the ECfunded project CoSyne (FP7- ICT-4-248531). The authors would also like to acknowledge Pamela Forner and Giovanni Moretti from CELCT, and the volunteer translators that contributed to the creation of the dataset: Giusi Calo, Victoria Díaz, Bianca Jeremias, Anne Kauffman, Laura López Ortiz, Julie Mailfait, Laura Morán Iglesias, Andreas Schwab.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cosyne: Synchronizing multilingual wiki content</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Amit</forename><surname>Bronner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Matteo</forename><surname>Negri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yashar</forename><surname>Mehdad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Angela</forename><surname>Fahrni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Christof</forename><surname>Monz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of WikiSym</title>
				<meeting>WikiSym</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Libsvm: a library for support vector machines</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Chih-Chung</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Chih-Jen</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACM Transactions on Intelligent Systems and Technology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">27</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<publisher>TIST</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Probabilistic Textual Entailment: Generic Applied Modeling of Language Variability</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ido</forename><surname>Dagan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Oren</forename><surname>Glickman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the PASCAL Workshop of Learning Methods for Text Understanding and Mining</title>
				<meeting>the PASCAL Workshop of Learning Methods for Text Understanding and Mining</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unimelb: Cross-lingual Textual Entailment with Word Alignment and String Similarity Features</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yvette</forename><surname>Graham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Bahar</forename><surname>Salehi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tim</forename><surname>Baldwin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 7th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation</title>
				<meeting>the 7th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">ECNUCS: Recognizing Cross-lingual Textual Entailment Using Multiple Feature Types</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Zhao</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lan</forename><surname>Man</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 7th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation</title>
				<meeting>the 7th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Soft Cardinality-CLTE: Learning to Identify Directional Cross-Lingual Entailmens from Cardinalities and SMT</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sergio</forename><surname>Jimenez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Claudia</forename><surname>Becerra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><surname>Gelbukh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 7th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation</title>
				<meeting>the 7th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An opensource package for recognizing textual entailment</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Milen</forename><surname>Kouylekov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Matteo</forename><surname>Negri</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ACL 2010 System Demonstrations</title>
				<meeting>the ACL 2010 System Demonstrations</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Celi: EDITS and Generic Text Pair Classification</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Milen</forename><surname>Kouylekov</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 7th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation</title>
				<meeting>the 7th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automated Sense Disambiguation Using Machine-readable Dictionaries: How to Tell a Pine Cone from an Ice Cream Cone</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Lesk</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 5th annual international conference on Systems documentation (SIGDOC86)</title>
				<meeting>the 5th annual international conference on Systems documentation (SIGDOC86)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Towards Cross-Lingual Textual Entailment</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yashar</forename><surname>Mehdad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Matteo</forename><surname>Negri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Marcello</forename><surname>Federico</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 11th Annual Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (NAACL HLT 2010)</title>
				<meeting>the 11th Annual Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (NAACL HLT 2010)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using Bilingual Parallel Corpora for Cross-Lingual Textual Entailment</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yashar</forename><surname>Mehdad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Matteo</forename><surname>Negri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Marcello</forename><surname>Federico</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 49th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies (ACL HLT</title>
				<meeting>the 49th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies (ACL HLT</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Detecting Semantic Equivalence and Information Disparity in Cross-lingual Documents</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yashar</forename><surname>Mehdad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Matteo</forename><surname>Negri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Marcello</forename><surname>Federico</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 50th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
				<meeting>the 50th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cosyne: a framework for multilingual content synchronization of wikis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Christof</forename><surname>Monz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Vivi</forename><surname>Nastase</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Matteo</forename><surname>Negri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Angela</forename><surname>Fahrni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yashar</forename><surname>Mehdad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Strube</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of WikiSym</title>
				<meeting>WikiSym</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Creating a Bilingual Entailment Corpus through Translations with Mechanical Turk: $100 for a 10-day Rush</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Matteo</forename><surname>Negri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yashar</forename><surname>Mehdad</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the NAACL HLT 2010 Workshop on Creating Speech and Language Data with Amazonś Mechanical Turk</title>
				<meeting>the NAACL HLT 2010 Workshop on Creating Speech and Language Data with Amazonś Mechanical Turk</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Towards extensible textual entailment engines: the edits package</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Matteo</forename><surname>Negri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Milen</forename><surname>Kouylekov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Bernardo</forename><surname>Magnini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yashar</forename><surname>Mehdad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Elena</forename><surname>Cabrio</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">AI* IA 2009: Emergent Perspectives in Artificial Intelligence</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="314" to="323" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Matto</forename><surname>Negri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Luisa</forename><surname>Bentivogli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yashar</forename><surname>Mehdad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Danilo</forename><surname>Giampiccolo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alessandro</forename><surname>Marchetti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Divide and Conquer: Crowdsourcing the Creation of Cross-Lingual Textual Entailment Corpora. Proceedings of the 2011 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Semeval-2012 Task 8: Cross-lingual Textual Entailment for Content Synchronization</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Matteo</forename><surname>Negri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alessandro</forename><surname>Marchetti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yashar</forename><surname>Mehdad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Luisa</forename><surname>Bentivogli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Danilo</forename><surname>Giampiccolo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 6th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation</title>
				<meeting>the 6th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Chinese Whispers: Cooperative Paraphrase Acquisition</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Matteo</forename><surname>Negri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yashar</forename><surname>Mehdad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alessandro</forename><surname>Marchetti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Danilo</forename><surname>Giampiccolo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Luisa</forename><surname>Bentivogli</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Eight International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC12)</title>
				<meeting>the Eight International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC12)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2659" to="2665" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A systematic comparison of various statistical alignment models</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Och</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Ney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Josef</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">O</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Ney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">ALTN: Word Alignment Features for Cross-Lingual Textual Entailment</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Marco</forename><surname>Turchi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Matteo</forename><surname>Negri</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 7th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation</title>
				<meeting>the 7th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">BUAP: N -gram based Feature Evaluation for the Cross-Lingual Textual Entailment Task</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Darnes</forename><surname>Vilariño</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Pinto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Saul</forename><surname>León</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yuridiana</forename><surname>Alemán</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Helena</forename><surname>Gómez-Adorno</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 7th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation</title>
				<meeting>the 7th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
